Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and we're going to a family party today, right Marco?
我是Catherine，我们今天要去参加一个家庭聚会，对吧，Marco？
That's right.
没错。
We're going to go see our family, our relatives and we're going to talk about all the different
我们要去看望我们的家人、亲戚，并且我们会讨论所有不同的
family members that you can have.
你可能有的家庭成员。
So, there are some very, very specific family members that sometimes you don't really know
所以，有一些非常非常具体的家庭成员，有时候你并不真正知道
the names of.
他们的称呼。
That's right.
没错。
So, we're not talking about mother, father, brother, sister.
所以，我们不是在谈论妈妈、爸爸、兄弟、姐妹。
We're talking about what we call in English extended family.
我们在谈论英语中所谓的“大家庭”。
So, that means not just the people you live with but also people you're related to who
也就是说，不仅包括和你住在一起的人，还包括那些
are maybe in different parts of your family.
可能在你家庭其他分支的亲戚。
That's right.
没错。
So, let's listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
那么，让我们听一下对话，我们一会儿回来。
What are you doing this weekend?
你这个周末打算做什么？
My brother-in-law is having a small get-together at his house and he invited me.
我姐夫在他家办了个小型聚会，他邀请了我。
Is it a family thing or just friends?
是家庭聚会还是只是朋友聚会？
A bit of both.
两者都有。
Some cousins, aunts and uncles will be there but also some friends from the neighborhood.
一些堂表亲、阿姨和叔叔会去，还有一些邻居朋友。
Is your great-uncle Rick going to be there?
你的叔祖父Rick会去吗？
He is really funny.
他真的很搞笑。
Yeah, he's going to be there with his stepson and his ex-wife.
是啊，他会带着他的继子和前妻一起去。
You mean your sister?
你是说我姐姐？
No, Rick is actually my great-uncle so he's my grandmother's brother.
不，Rick其实是我的叔祖父，所以他是我奶奶的兄弟。
You lost me.
你把我搞糊涂了。
I'll explain later.
我晚点再解释。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Alright, so now let's talk about these family members on Language Takeaway.
好了，现在让我们在“语言要点”环节讨论这些家庭成员。
Language Takeaway
语言要点
So, Marco, we've got four family members to talk about today.
那么，Marco，我们今天要讨论四个家庭成员。
And the first one is brother-in-law.
第一个是“brother-in-law”。
Right, so we have the word brother-in-law.
对，我们有“brother-in-law”这个词。
So, basically this person is married to your sister.
基本上，这个人是你姐姐或妹妹的丈夫。
That's right.
没错。
So, I have a brother, I have a sister.
所以，我有一个兄弟，我有一个姐妹。
But when these people marry, they marry someone who I'm not related to by blood.
但当这些人结婚时，他们娶或嫁的人和我没有血缘关系。
We call them in-laws, so brother-in-law, sister-in-law.
我们称他们为“in-laws”，所以有“brother-in-law”、“sister-in-law”。
Right, so that's exactly it.
对，就是这样。
The key there is that when it has the ending in-law, it means that you're not related to them by blood.
关键在于，当词尾有“in-law”时，意味着你和他们没有血缘关系。
It's your extended family because of marriage.
他们是因婚姻而结成的大家庭成员。
That's right.
没错。
So, I have a younger brother.
所以，我有一个弟弟。
When he gets married, I will have a sister-in-law.
当他结婚时，我就会有一个嫂子或弟媳。
That's right.
没错。
And it applies to, for example, father-in-law.
这也适用于，比如，“father-in-law”。
That would be your husband's dad or mother-in-law would be your husband's mother.
那会是你丈夫的爸爸，或者“mother-in-law”会是你丈夫的妈妈。
Yeah, so these are all related to you by marriage.
是的，这些都是通过婚姻和你联系在一起的。
All right, so now moving on to the next type of extended family member that we have is a stepson.
好了，现在我们来看下一种大家庭成员，那就是“stepson”。
Your uncle has a stepson.
你叔叔有一个继子。
So, a stepson.
所以，“stepson”。
Now, this can get very confusing.
这可能会让人很困惑。
Let's take a simple, simple family.
我们举一个简单的家庭例子。
We have two people and they're married.
有两个人，他们结婚了。
Right.
对。
And then they get divorced, so they split up.
然后他们离婚了，所以分开了。
And now maybe they had some kids.
现在，也许他们之前有孩子。
The wife has kids, and she gets married to someone else.
妻子有孩子，然后她嫁给了别人。
So, her new husband calls her son his stepson.
所以，她的新丈夫把她的儿子称为他的继子。
Right.
对。
Because it's not his son.
因为那不是他的亲生儿子。
It's another man's son.
那是另一个男人的儿子。
Right.
对。
But they're still related by marriage.
但他们仍然通过婚姻联系在一起。
So, when your new husband or your new wife has kids from another marriage, they're called stepson, stepdaughter.
所以，当你的新丈夫或新妻子有来自另一段婚姻的孩子时，他们被称为继子、继女。
That's right.
没错。
So, it's the same thing as if my mother got divorced and she remarried.
所以，这就像如果我妈妈离婚了，然后她再婚。
She has a new husband.
她有了一个新丈夫。
That man would be my stepfather.
那个男人就会是我的继父。
All right, so these are all family members.
好了，这些都是家庭成员。
When you hear the word step, family members that we have because of divorce.
当你听到“step”这个词时，指的是因离婚而产生的家庭成员。
So, stepson, stepdaughter, stepfather, stepmother.
所以，继子、继女、继父、继母。
All right, and now, again, related to the whole divorce thing, the person that you get divorced to is called an ex-wife or an ex-husband.
好了，现在，再次与离婚相关，你离婚的那个人被称为前妻或前夫。
All right, so ex, like ex-girlfriend or ex-boyfriend means previous.
对，“ex”就像前女友或前男友，意思是“之前的”。
So, my ex-wife is someone I was married to before or in the case of a woman, my ex-husband was someone I was married to before, but we got divorced.
所以，我的前妻是我以前结过婚的人，或者对女性来说，我的前夫是我以前结过婚的人，但我们离婚了。
So, we're not married now.
所以我们现在不是夫妻了。
That's exactly it.
就是这样。
So, it only applies to husband and wife, right?
所以，它只适用于丈夫和妻子，对吧？
You don't say my ex-children or my ex-mother-in-law.
你不会说“我的前孩子”或“我的前岳母”。
Well, because your children are always your children.
嗯，因为你的孩子永远是你的孩子。
All right.
好的。
Exactly.
没错。
If you talk about your ex-wife's parents, you just say my ex-wife's father or my ex-wife's mother because there's no more in-law.
如果你谈论前妻的父母，你只需说“我前妻的父亲”或“我前妻的母亲”，因为不再有姻亲关系了。
There's no law.
没有姻亲关系了。
You're not married.
你们没结婚。
Right, okay.
对，好的。
And lastly, now we have an uncle, but just not any uncle.
最后，现在我们有一个叔叔，但可不是普通的叔叔。
We have our great uncle.
我们有我们的叔祖父。
Great uncle.
叔祖父。
So, they actually explain this in the dialogue.
所以，他们在对话中确实解释了这个。
They say, he is my grandmother's brother.
他们说，他是我祖母的兄弟。
Right.
对。
Okay, so my uncle, this is simple.
好的，所以我的叔叔，这很简单。
My uncle is my mother's brother or my father's brother.
我的叔叔是我母亲的兄弟或我父亲的兄弟。
Easy.
简单。
But my great uncle is one of my grandparent's brothers.
但我的叔祖父是我祖父母之一的兄弟。
Right.
对。
So, my grandmother's brother or my grandfather's brother.
所以，是我祖母的兄弟或我祖父的兄弟。
Right.
对。
In English, we don't distinguish.
在英语中，我们不区分。
We don't say a different word for grandmother's brother or grandfather's brother.
我们不会用不同的词来称呼祖母的兄弟或祖父的兄弟。
Right, right, exactly.
对，对，没错。
So, your great uncle could be either your grandmother's brother or your grandfather's brother.
所以，你的叔祖父可能是你祖母的兄弟或你祖父的兄弟。
That's right.
没错。
So, in my family, I have, well, I just have one great uncle and one great aunt.
所以，在我的家庭里，我只有一个叔祖父和一个姑奶奶。
My grandmother has a sister, so I have a great aunt, and my grandfather has a brother, so I have a great uncle.
我祖母有一个姐妹，所以我有一个姑奶奶，我祖父有一个兄弟，所以我有一个叔祖父。
And now, the prefix great can also be applied, for example, to grandparents.
现在，前缀“great”也可以用在祖父母上。
So, you can say, my great grandfather.
所以，你可以说，我的曾祖父。
That's right.
没错。
So, we're talking about generations.
所以，我们在谈论世代。
I have a grandfather, but his father is my great grandfather.
我有一个祖父，但他的父亲是我的曾祖父。
That means we go back in the past one more generation.
这意味着我们往过去回溯了一代。
That's right.
没错。
All right, so let's take a break and let's listen to the dialogue again.
好的，那我们休息一下，再听一遍对话。
What are you doing this weekend?
这个周末你打算做什么？
My brother-in-law is having a small get-together at his house, and he invited me.
我的姐夫在他家办一个小聚会，他邀请了我。
Is it a family thing or just friends?
是家庭聚会还是只有朋友？
A bit of both.
两者都有。
Some cousins, aunts, and uncles will be there, but also some friends from the neighborhood.
一些堂表亲、阿姨和叔叔会去，还有一些邻居朋友。
Is your great uncle Rick going to be there?
你的叔祖父里克会去吗？
He is really funny.
他真的很搞笑。
Yeah, he's going to be there with his stepson and his ex-wife.
是啊，他会和他的继子以及前妻一起去。
You mean your sister?
你是说我姐姐？
No, Rick is actually my great uncle, so he's my grandmother's brother.
不，里克实际上是我的叔祖父，所以他是我祖母的兄弟。
You lost me.
你把我搞糊涂了。
I'll explain later.
我待会儿解释。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
All right, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So, we've picked out three key phrases for you.
所以，我们为你挑选了三个关键短语。
Let's take a look at those now on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们在流利度构建器上看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
All right, so on Fluency Builder, we have a great noun here, actually.
好的，在流利度构建器上，我们有一个很棒的名词。
You might have heard this before in a different way, but in today's dialogue, we're talking
你可能以前以不同的方式听过它，但在今天的对话中，我们谈论的是
about a small get-together.
一个小聚会。
My brother-in-law is having a small get-together.
我的姐夫在办一个小聚会。
Now, what is a get-together, Mark?
那么，什么是聚会，马克？
Right, so as you notice, we say a get-together, meaning that get-together, we are taking it
对，正如你注意到的，我们说“a get-together”，意思是“聚会”，我们把它当作
as a noun.
一个名词。
And it may be confusing because you see the verb get, right?
这可能让人困惑，因为你看到了动词“get”，对吧？
And you're thinking it's a verb, but no.
你会以为它是动词，但不是。
A get-together is a reunion, a meeting.
“A get-together”就是一次团聚、一次会面。
All right, a party.
好的，一个派对。
A party.
一个派对。
So, maybe it's a very informal party, very casual.
所以，可能是一个非常非正式的派对，很随意。
Not fancy.
不花哨。
A get-together.
一个聚会。
I could say, Marco, I'm having a get-together at my apartment.
我可以说，马可，我在公寓里办个聚会。
Do you want to come and bring your girlfriend?
你想来并带上你的女朋友吗？
Right, so very simple.
对，很简单。
Maybe we have a drink or some food, but it's nothing fancy.
也许我们喝点东西或吃点东西，但不是什么花哨的。
That's right.
没错。
Very informal, very casual.
非常非正式，非常随意。
A get-together.
一个聚会。
And when we were asking about the get-together, we asked if it's a family thing or is it just
当我们问起这个聚会时，我们问的是“是家庭聚会还是只有
friends?
朋友？”
So, I want to take a look at this phrase here, a family thing.
所以，我想看看这里的这个短语，“家庭聚会”。
Is it a family thing?
是家庭聚会吗？
What am I asking when I say, okay, Marco, this party you're having, is it a family thing?
当我说“好的，马可，你办的派对，是家庭聚会吗？”时，我在问什么？
Well, you're asking if it's a family reunion, a family party.
嗯，你在问这是不是家庭团聚、家庭派对。
So, that means if I'm not in your family, can I still come?
所以，这意味着如果我不是你家人，我还能来吗？
Right.
对。
Right, because if it's a family thing, it's just for people in my family.
对，因为如果是家庭聚会，那就只针对我家人。
Right, right.
对，对。
If it's for everyone, no problem.
如果是面向所有人，那就没问题。
But I don't want to go to your house if it's a family thing because that's private.
但如果是家庭聚会，我就不想去你家，因为那是私人的。
Right, so usually, for example, maybe Christmas dinner would usually be a family thing.
对，所以通常来说，比如圣诞晚餐一般是家庭聚会。
You celebrate it with your family mostly, but it's not always a family thing.
你主要和家人一起庆祝，但也不总是家庭聚会。
That's right.
没错。
I could say, this year my birthday is just a family thing.
我可以说，今年我的生日只是家庭聚会。
I'm only inviting family members.
我只邀请家人。
Exactly.
完全正确。
All right, and lastly, we got a little bit confused with the great uncle and the stepson
好了，最后，我们对“叔祖父”和“继子”有点搞混了，
and the ex-wife.
还有“前妻”。
And so, we said, you know what?
然后我们说，你知道吗？
You lost me.
你把我搞糊涂了。
Now, this is another great phrase.
现在，这是另一个很棒的短语。
The phrase means, I don't understand.
这个短语的意思是，我不明白。
I'm confused.
我糊涂了。
Right, that's exactly it.
对，就是这样。
So, if someone is explaining something and I don't understand, then you can say, you
所以，如果有人解释某事而我不明白，你就可以说，你
know what?
知道吗？
You lost me.
你把我搞糊涂了。
I don't understand.
我不明白。
Right, and sometimes I say this when someone is giving a very long explanation for something.
对，有时候当有人对某事做很长的解释时，我会这么说。
So, to get to my house, you turn left here and then you go two blocks, you turn right
所以，去我家，你在这里左转，然后走两个街区，右转，
and you go straight and you wait for the stoplight.
直走，等红绿灯。
And then you go to the right-hand corner, there's a store.
然后到右边角落，那里有个商店。
I say, wait, wait, wait.
我说，等等，等等。
You lost me.
你把我搞糊涂了。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
I don't understand.
我不明白。
I'm confused.
我糊涂了。
That's right.
没错。
All right, so that's all we have.
好了，这就是我们所有的内容。
Let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
让我们最后再听一遍对话。
What are you doing this weekend?
你这周末做什么？
My brother-in-law is having a small get-together at his house and he invited me.
我姐夫在他家办了个小型聚会，他邀请了我。
Is it a family thing or just friends?
是家庭聚会还是朋友聚会？
A bit of both.
两者都有。
Some cousins, aunts and uncles will be there, but also some friends from the neighborhood.
一些堂表亲、阿姨和叔叔会去，还有一些邻居朋友。
Is your great-uncle Rick going to be there?
你的叔祖父里克会去吗？
He is really funny.
他真有趣。
Yeah, he's going to be there with his stepson and his ex-wife.
是的，他会带着他的继子和前妻一起去。
You mean your sister?
你是说你姐姐？
No, Rick is actually my great-uncle, so he's my grandmother's brother.
不，里克实际上是我的叔祖父，所以他是我祖母的兄弟。
You lost me.
你把我搞糊涂了。
I'll explain later.
我待会儿解释。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
So, speaking of extended family members, what else can we mention?
那么，说到大家庭成员，我们还能提到什么？
We have stepfamily, your stepson, your stepdaughter.
我们有继亲家庭，你的继子，你的继女。
What about if you have an adopted child?
如果你有收养的孩子呢？
Would you differentiate it?
你会区分吗？
Some people do, some people don't.
有些人会，有些人不会。
Most people just say, this is my son, this is my daughter.
大多数人只是说，这是我儿子，这是我女儿。
But I would like to add that with stepson, stepdaughter, it's not just divorce that we have this.
但我想补充一点，对于继子、继女，不只是离婚才会有这种情况。
Also, if the parent, maybe the mother dies and the father has a new wife,
还有，如果父母中一方，比如母亲去世了，父亲有了新妻子，
then the new wife can say, this is my stepson, this is my stepdaughter.
那么新妻子可以说，这是我的继子，这是我的继女。
So, there are two possibilities.
所以，有两种可能性。
One is death and one is remarriage because of divorce.
一种是死亡，另一种是因离婚而再婚。
But as far as adopted, no, usually just say my son and my daughter.
但至于收养，通常只说我的儿子和我的女儿。
But I can tell you this.
但我可以告诉你这个。
If my father and my mother divorce, my father has a new wife, and together they have a baby,
如果我父亲和我母亲离婚，我父亲有了新妻子，他们一起生了个孩子，
the baby, boy or girl, is my half-brother or half-sister because we share one parent, my father.
这个孩子，不管是男孩还是女孩，是我的同父异母兄弟或姐妹，因为我们共享一个父亲。
Right. This is very interesting.
对。这很有趣。
So, if you do have a brother or sister that is not from your same mother or father,
所以，如果你有一个兄弟或姐妹，不是来自同一个母亲或父亲，
but just one parent, then yeah, it's called a half-brother or sister.
而是只有一个共同父母，那么是的，这叫做同父异母或同母异父的兄弟或姐妹。
Half, remember this, half because half of their parents are the same as your parents.
记住，“半”是因为他们一半的父母和你的父母相同。
Maybe one father or mother.
可能是一个父亲或母亲。
But with stepbrothers and stepsisters, the only reason you're related is because of marriage, not because of blood.
但对于继兄弟和继姐妹，你们有关系的唯一原因是婚姻，而不是血缘。
Right. We didn't mention that you could have a stepbrother.
对。我们没提到你可能有继兄弟。
So, it's your brother, but he's legally your brother, but he's not related to your father or anyone in your family.
所以，他是你的兄弟，但法律上是你的兄弟，但他和你父亲或你家人没有血缘关系。
That's right. That's right.
没错。没错。
So, maybe you have many stepbrothers.
所以，也许你有很多继兄弟。
You could have a stepbrother and a half-brother.
你可能有一个继兄弟和一个同父异母的兄弟。
So, there are lots of different combinations because of many different reasons.
所以，由于很多不同的原因，有很多不同的组合。
All right, guys. That's all the time we have for today.
好了，各位。我们今天就到这里。
But it's a little bit of a confusing topic.
但这有点让人困惑的话题。
So, if you have any questions or any doubts, you can come to our website, EnglishPod.com, and you can leave them there.
所以，如果你有任何问题或疑问，可以来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在那里留言。
Yeah, we hope to see you guys online. And until next time.
是啊，我们希望能在线见到你们。下次再见。
Bye.
拜拜。